Guide to the Paul Oskar Kristeller Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Paul Oskar Kristeller Papers
1905-1998 [Bulk Dates: 1941-1997]
Kristeller, Paul Oskar, 1905-1999.
114.78 linear feet (171 boxes; 81 document boxes, 72 record storage cartons, 18 notecard boxes)
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4079550
Professional and personal papers of the German émigré scholar Paul Oskar Kristeller. Kristeller was a professor of philosophy at Columbia University and a world renowned scholar of Renaissance humanism and Renaissance philosophy who published widely, notably his major catalog of uncataloged manuscript from the Italian Renaissance, the Iter Italicum.
Biographical Note
Paul Oskar Kristeller, the Frederick Woodbridge Professor Emeritus of Philosophy, was a major scholar of Renaissance philosophy and Renaissance humanism.
Paul Oskar Kristeller was born Paul Oskar Gräfenberg on May 22, 1905 in Berlin Germany to well-to-do Jewish parents. Paul Oskar's father, Oskar Gräfenber, was a merchant who died of a heart attack shortly after Paul Oskar's birth. In 1911 Alice Magnus married the wealthy industrialist Heinrich Kristeller, whose last name Paul Oskar Kristeller adopted in 1919.
Kristeller, always intellectually curious, attended school at the Mommsen Gymnasium in Berlin starting in 1914 and graduating with honors in 1923. The curriculum included an extensive foreign language program, including 12 years of Latin training. In 1923 Kristeller started college, studying philosophy, medieval history, and mathematics at Heidelberg, Freiburg, and Marburg between the years 1923-1928. He went on to continue his studies at the University of Heidelberg, earning his PhD in 1928 with a thesis on Plotinus. He went on to do a Habilitation with Martin Heidegger in Freiburg, writing his Habilitationsschrift on the fifteenth century Platonist Marsilio Ficino, a thinker that would continue to figure in Kristeller's scholarship throughout his career.
The rise of the National Socialist government in Germany and their racist and anti-Semitic policies put an end to Kristeller's academic career in Germany in 1933. With his career in Germany cut short, Kristeller went to Italy where he taught German at a number of schools and Universities including the Istitito Superiore di Magistero in Florence and the Scuola Normale Superiore of Pisa and the University of Pisa, where he also received the degree of Dottore in Filosofia in 1937. He remained in Italy, studying and teaching until 1938, but as the Mussolini regime gained more power in Italy, Kristeller began his attempts to secure an academic position in the United States. He eventually received an invitation to teach a graduate seminar at Yale University in 1939, and he remained based in the United States for the rest of his life, becoming a US citizen in 1945.
Kristeller obtained a permanent faculty position in the Department of Philosophy at Columbia University in the fall of 1939 where he was to spend the rest of his professional career. He was promoted to the rank of full professor in 1956 and taught classes, gave lectures until his retirement in 1973. Even after his retirement, Kristeller remained an active member of the Columbia Community giving occasional lectures and continuing his own research and scholarly projects up until the time of his death in 1999.
Kristeller was an internationally recognized scholar on the intellectual history of the Renaissance. He published widely, including a book length study on Marsilio Ficino and hundreds of articles on topics in Renaissance humanistic thought and Renaissance medicine. Though his scholarship is prodigious, he is probably best known for his work compiling research guides and manuscript catalogs, particularly his magnum opus the Iter Italicum, a seven volume catalog of previously uncataloged humanistic manuscripts.
Kristeller received many academic honors and accolades over the course of his career. He was a Fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, received a Guggenheim fellowship, and was awarded a Macarthur "genius" award. Kristeller was a member of editorial board of the =Journal of the History of Ideas, and was a founding member, and president, of the Renaissance Society of America.
In 1940 Kristeller married Edith Lind Lewinnek, another German Jewish émigré from Hamburg. Edith Kristeller received a diploma in physical therapy from New York University, and her medical degree from the Women's Medical College of Pennsylvania. She spent most of her career working in rehabilitative medicine at various New York City hospitals. Edith Lind Kristeller died in 1992.
Paul Oskar Kristeller died on June 7, 1999 at the age of 94.
Scope and Content
This collection documents the professional, and to a lesser extent, the personal life of Paul Oskar Kristeller, a professor of philosopher and scholar of Renaissance philosophy and Renaissance humanism. The collection contains material related to Kristeller's teaching and professional activities, as well as a large number of manuscripts of articles, essays, lectures, and books written or edited by Kristeller. In addition to manuscripts, the collections contains correspondence (both personal and professional in nature), research notes, photographs, and a large series of material related to the research, writing, and publication of his major work of scholarship the Iter Italicum, a catalog of unprocessed Italian humanistic manuscripts.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in VIII series
Series I: Correspondence, 1926-1998
Subseries I.1: General Correspondence, 1920-1995
Subseries I.2: Family and Personal Correspondence, 1913-1997
Series II: Personal and Biographical Material, 1905-1997
Series III: Professional Activities, 1941-1996
Subseries III.1: General, 1941-1996
Subseries III.2: Catalogus Translationum et Commentariorum, 1942-1986
Subseries III.3: Committee to Rescue Italian Art (CRIA), 1966-1968
Subseries III.4: Journal of the History of Ideas, 1941-1987
Subseries III.5: Professional Contacts
Series IV: Columbia University, 1939-1989
Subseries IV.1: Subject Files, 1939-1968
Subseries IV.2: Correspondence, 1941-1989
Subseries IV.3: University Seminars 1945-1976
Subseries IV.4: Course Notes, 1940-1978
Series V: Writings, 1926-1995
Subseries V.1: Manuscripts-- Books and Major Works, 1926-1992
Subseries V.2: Articles and Essays, 1926-1995
Subseries V.3: Lectures and Speeches, 1940-1993
Subseries V.4: Festschrifts and Memorials, 1978-1993
Subseries V.5: Book Reviews, 1930-1995
Series VI: Iter Italicum, 1949-1997
Subseries VI.1: Research, 1949-1986
Subseries VI.2: Editorial and Administrative Files, 1949-1997
Subseries VI.3: Manuscript, 1987-1997
Series VII: Notebooks and Notes, 1920-1990
Subseries VII.1: Notebooks on the History of Universities, 1940s-1987
Subseries VII.2: Unidentified Notebooks, undated, 1945-1946
Subseries VII.3: Research and Topical Notes, 1920-1990
Subseries VII.4: Research Notecards
Series VIII: Printed Material
Subjects
American Council of Learned Societies.; Columbia University.; Committee to Rescue Italian Art.; International Federation of Renaissance Societies.; Medieval Academy of America.; National Endowment for the Humanities.; Renaissance Society of America.; Ficino, Marsilio, 1433-1499.; Kristeller, Paul Oskar, 1905-1999.--Iter Italicum.; Pomponazzi, Pietro, 1462-1525.; Europe--Intellectual life.; Germany--History--20th century.; Antisemitism.; Authors, Latin--To 1700.; Civilization, Medieval.; Civilization, Modern.; Classical education.; Classical literature.; Emigration and immigration.; Humanism.; Intellectual life--History.; Latin language, Medieval and modern--Study and teaching.; Latin literature, Medieval and modern--Bio-bibliography.; Manuscripts, Greek.; Manuscripts, Latin.; Middle Ages.; Philosophy.; Philosophy, Renaissance.; Renaissance.; Scholarly publishing.; Addresses.; Articles.; Bibliographies.; Brochures.; Card files.; Essays.; Festschriften.; Handbills.; Invitations.; Lectures.; Lecture notes.; Minutes.; Notes.; Notebooks.; Obituaries.; Photographs.; Posters.; Reports.; Reviews.; Speeches.; Theses.; Editors.; College teachers.; Philosophers.; Scholars.; Journal of Philosophy.; Journal of the History of Ideas.
Gift of Paul Oskar Kristeller, 1977, 1980-1998
Access Restrictions
This collection is located on-site.
This collection has no restrictions.
Selected Related Material-- at Columbia
Catalogus et Commentariorum Records
- Series I: Correspondence, 1926-1998
  This series contains Paul Oskar Kristeller's correspondence, incoming as well as some carbons of outgoing correspondence. The series is divided into two suberies, the first is General Correspondence that focuses on correspondence with professional contacts and the second is Personal and Family Correspondence which has a more personal focus.
  - Subseries I.1: General Correspondence, 1920-1995
    This subseries contains professional and personal correspondence spanning the majority of Kristeller's career. Kristeller often kept carbons of outgoing correspondence. When those carbons are available they are filed with the letters to which they respond.
    - Aaters-Abrahamson, 1950-1997 (Box 1)
    - Abrahamson, Ernst, 1920-1958 (Box 1)
    - Academe-Adelmann, 1934-1999 (Box 1)
    - Adelmann, Franziska Grafin, 1976-1994 (Box 1)
    - Adelmann-Agresto, 1961-1996 (Box 1)
    - Aguzzi, Danilo 1959-1994 (Box 1)
    - Aiardi-Allen, 1936-1998 (Box 1)
    - Allen-Aly 1939-1998 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Michael, 1941-1998 (Box 1)
    - Ameisenowa, Zofia, 1959-1967 (Box 1)
    - Amaduzzi-Amtsgericht, 1935-1998 (Box 2)
    - Anshen, Ruth Nanda, 1940-1996, (2 Folders) (Box 2)
    - Analecta Bollandiana-Antonopulos, 1945-1995 (Box 2)
    - Appelbaum-Artz, 1952-1993 (Box 2)
    - Ascher-Ayres, 1938-1997 (Box 2)
    - Baader-Babinger, 1956-1993 (Box 2)
    - Baca-Bainton, 1951-1997 (Box 3)
    - Bainton, Roland, 1934-1991 (Box 3)
    - Baker-Smith -Banti (Box 3)
    - Baragiola- Baron 1951-1998 (Box 3)
    - Baron, Hans, 1932-1998, (2 Folders) (Box 3)
    - Baron-Barzun, 1940-1987 (Box 3)
    - Basanoff-Bausola, 1940-1980 (Box 4)
    - Baxandall-Behrends, 1951-1997 (Box 4)
    - Beardsley, Theodore, 1965-1993 (Box 4)
    - Beierwalters-Belloni, 1950-1996 (Box 4)
    - Bellanti-Bepler, 1930-1992 (Box 4)
    - Beranek-Bernardini, 1939-1991 (Box 4)
    - Bernardo-Bertalanffy, 1939-1998 (Box 4)
    - Bertalot, Ludwig, undated, 1933-1975, (4 Folders) (Box 5)
    - Bertalot-Biberman, 1937-1998 (Box 5)
    - Bibliographical Society of America- Bibliotheque Nationale, 1952-1998 (Box 5)
    - Bickerman-Bieler, 1945-1994 (Box 5)
    - Biemel-Bilgrami, 1943-1993 (Box 5)
    - Billanovich, Giusseppe, 1938-1998 (Box 6)
    - Billeter-Blackwell, 1950-1994 (Box 6)
    - Blackwell-Blauner, 1939-1996 (Box 6)
    - Bleiberg-Blouin, 1958-1992 (Box 6)
    - Blue Card-Bly, 1935-1996 (Box 6)
    - Board of Elections-Boehner, 1938-1996 (Box 6)
    - Boer, Elisabeth, 1979-1989 (Box 6)
    - Boer, Emilie, 1939-1980, (3 Folders) (Box 7)
    - Boeren-Bokholtz, 1952-1993 (Box 7)
    - Bolchert- Boltoni, 1952-1993 (Box 7)
    - Bonacossi-Bonville, 1943-1998 (Box 7)
    - Boon-Bouwsma, 1946-1997 (Box 7)
    - Bowden-Bozzoli, 1939-1996 (Box 8)
    - Bracken-Branco, 1939-1995 (Box 8)
    - Branca, Vittore, 1946-1998 (Box 8)
    - Brancaccio-Breen, 1945-1993 (Box 8)
    - Brehier-Brizio, 1930-1998 (Box 8)
    - Brock-Brotje (Box 8)
    - Brown, A-E (Box 8)
    - Brown, H-T, 1945-1997 (Box 9)
    - Brown, Virginia, 1968-1996, (2 Folders) (Box 9)
    - Brown, Virginia, 1988-1996 (Box 9)
    - Browne-Buhler, 1948-1985 (Box 9)
    - Buhler- Buki, 1957-1984 (Box 9)
    - Bull-Bulst, 1951-1994 (Box 9)
    - Bulst, Walther, 1924-1986, (4 Folders) (Box 10)
    - Bulst-Burk, 1957-1996 (Box 10)
    - Burke-Byron, 1939-1993 (Box 10)
    - Cabiate-Camins (Box 10)
    - Cammelli- Cantelupe (Box 11)
    - Cantimori-Caplow (Box 11)
    - Caponigri (Box 11)
    - Capovilla- Carlson (Box 11)
    - Carmi-Cartwright (Box 11)
    - Casamassima- Catalano (Box 11)
    - Catanzariti-Ceserani (Box 11)
    - Chadwyck-Cherner (Box 11)
    - Cherniss, Harold, 1953-1985 (Box 12)
    - Chernow- Cilento (Box 12)
    - Ciliberto-Clare (Box 12)
    - Citron, Lisa, 1940-1957 (Box 12)
    - Clark (Box 12)
    - Clarke-Clopper (Box 12)
    - Clough, Cecil, 1955-1969 (Box 12)
    - Clough, Cecil, 1970-1998 (Box 13)
    - Clubb-Cochrane (Box 13)
    - Codignola, Ernesto, 1933-1956, (2 Folders) (Box 13)
    - Coffin-Colp (Box 13)
    - Columbia University-Conarroe (Box 13)
    - Concasty-Consagra (Box 13)
    - Constable (Box 13)
    - Constantin-Corbeau (Box 14)
    - Corbeau, A., 1967-1969 (Box 14)
    - Cordi-Corsi (Box 14)
    - Cortesi-Cramer (Box 14)
    - Cranz, E., 1956-1989, (3 Folders) (Box 14)
    - Cranz, E., 1985-1994 (Box 15)
    - Cranz-Crystal (Box 15)
    - Csapodi-Czoniczer (Box 15)
    - D'Archiardi-Dassaro (Box 15)
    - Daube-Deakins (Box 15)
    - DeAguilar-Defradas (Box 15)
    - DeGaetano (Box 15)
    - DeGandillac-Delibera (Box 16)
    - Della Terza-DeNegri (Box 16)
    - Denis-Desmond (Box 16)
    - DeSua-de Vogel (Box 16)
    - de Zayas- Dibner (Box 16)
    - Di Cesare- Dickson (Box 16)
    - Dieckmann, Herbert, 1933-1969 (Box 16)
    - Dieckmann, Jane and Louisette, 1933-1993 (Box 16)
    - Diener- Domandi (Box 17)
    - Domanski- Dorn (Box 17)
    - Dostalova-Downing, G. (Box 17)
    - Downing, P.- Dröge (Box 17)
    - Drummond- Dulles (Box 17)
    - Dullo- Dyson (Box 17)
    - East-Edman (Box 17)
    - Edwards, Bill, 1956-1994 (Box 17)
    - Edmunds-Ekman (Box 18)
    - Elder-Emerson (Box 18)
    - Emery-Engle (Box 18)
    - Entner- Everson (Box 18)
    - Fabbri- Fairchild (Box 18)
    - Falbord-Fayen (Box 18)
    - Fedden-Ferrante (Box 18)
    - Ferrara- Fever (Box 19)
    - Feinstel- Field (Box 19)
    - Fiering- Floriani (Box 19)
    - Floridi, Luciano, 1993-1997 (Box 19)
    - Florshiem- Forsyth (Box 19)
    - Foster- Foye (Box 19)
    - Fraenkel-Freedman (Box 19)
    - Freeman-Friess (Box 19)
    - Frijda- Fulton (Box 20)
    - Fumaroli- Fussel (Box 20)
    - Gabel- Gagnon (Box 20)
    - Gairon- Ganz (Box 20)
    - Garand- Gargan (Box 20)
    - Garin- Gay (Box 20)
    - Gentile, Giovanni, 1934-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 20)
    - Geankopios- Genovese (Box 20)
    - Gentile, Giovanni, 1934-1941 (POK to) (Box 21)
    - Gentile-Giacon (Box 21)
    - Giametti-Gilbert (Box 21)
    - Gilbert, Neal, 1951-1990 (Box 21)
    - Gilead-Giustl (Box 21)
    - Giustiani, Vito, 1939-1993 (Box 21)
    - Gladbach-Goldblatt (Box 21)
    - Goldbrunner, Herman, 1961-1998 (Box 21)
    - Golden-Golob (Box 22)
    - Gombach-Gorfunkel (Box 22)
    - Gorsten-Gosselin (Box 22)
    - Gotesky-Goudge (Box 22)
    - Goukovsky, Matvey (Box 22)
    - Gould-Grassi (Box 22)
    - Graubard-Green (Box 22)
    - Greenawalt-Greer (Box 22)
    - Greetham-Griffiths (Box 22)
    - Griggio-Grossman (Box 23)
    - Groves-Guerlac (Box 23)
    - Guerra-Guzzo (Box 23)
    - Haag-Hageman (Box 23)
    - Hagius-Haller (Box 23)
    - Halligan-Hanke (Box 23)
    - Hankins, James, 1978-1994 (Box 23)
    - Harkinson-Harrier (Box 23)
    - Harris-Hartt (Box 24)
    - Harnett-Harrington (Box 24)
    - Hartzell-Hawrylchak (Box 24)
    - Hay-Hayes (Box 24)
    - Headley-Hecksher (Box 24)
    - Heidegger, Martin, 1932-1978 (Box 24)
    - Heidelberg-Heitlman (Box 24)
    - Held, Julius, 1934-1998, (2 Folders) (Box 24)
    - Heller-Henderson (Box 24)
    - Hendley-Henze (Box 24)
    - Hepp-Herren (Box 24)
    - Herrera-Heymann (Box 25)
    - Hibbard- Hillerbrand (Box 25)
    - Hillgarth-Hire (Box 25)
    - Hirsch, Elizabeth, 1938-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 25)
    - Hirsch-Hitchcock (Box 25)
    - Hoag-Hoenigswald (Box 25)
    - Hoffman, Ernst, 1948-1950 (Box 25)
    - Hoffman, Hans P., 1925-1939 (Box 25)
    - Hoffman, Thea, 1954-1967 (Box 25)
    - Hoffman-Holwitz (Box 25)
    - Holzberg-Horner (Box 25)
    - Hornik, Henry, 1957-1967 (Box 26)
    - Hornstein-Hough (Box 26)
    - Houppert-Howard (Box 26)
    - Howard, Hubert, 1959-1987 (Box 26)
    - Howe-Hutchinson (Box 26)
    - Hutton, James, 1945-1972, (3 Folders) (Box 26)
    - Huggens-Hyman (Box 26)
    - Hyman, Ruth, 1975-1987 (Box 26)
    - Iacono-Ijsewish (Box 26)
    - Ilardi, Vincent, 1964-1993 (Box 26)
    - Iliescu-Irmsher (Box 27)
    - Irtenkauf- Izbicki (Box 27)
    - Jack-Jaeger (Box 27)
    - Jaffe-Jamet (Box 27)
    - Jankofsky-Jaspers (Box 27)
    - Jasperson, Ed., 1928-1987 (Box 27)
    - Jaumann-Jayawardene (Box 27)
    - Jayne, Sears, 1948-1993 (Box 27)
    - Jeanneret-Jilburg (Box 27)
    - Joachim- Johnson (Box 27)
    - Jonas-Journal (Box 27)
    - Juarez-Jutro (Box 28)
    - Jung, Eva Marie, 1950-1994 (Box 28)
    - Kaegi, Werner, 1970-1993 (Box 28)
    - Kaemf-Kahn (Box 28)
    - Kaiser-Kantrowitz (Box 28)
    - Kaphan-Katayama (Box 28)
    - Katz (Various) (Box 28)
    - Katenellenbogen-Kazzaz (Box 28)
    - Kearney-Keller (Box 28)
    - Kelley, Donald, 1960-1998 (Box 28)
    - Kellman-Kendler (Box 29)
    - Kendrick-Kerstein (Box 29)
    - Kessler, E., 1968-1993 (Box 29)
    - Keyes-Killy (Box 29)
    - Kim-Kinderman (Box 29)
    - King, Margaret, 1970-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 29)
    - King-Kirwin (Box 29)
    - Kirshner, Julius, 1969-1993 (Box 29)
    - Kisch, Guido, 1957-1984 (Box 29)
    - Kirkendale-Kiyomi (Box 29)
    - Klachko-Klosko (Box 29)
    - Klosterman-Kluxen (Box 30)
    - Knachel-Knox (Box 30)
    - Knauer, E.G., 1964-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 30)
    - Knauer, G.N., 1968-1991 (Box 30)
    - Kanuer, Kezia, 1972-1985 (Box 30)
    - Koch-Kohl (Box 30)
    - Kohler-Koyre (Box 30)
    - Kra-Kraye (Box 30)
    - Krautter, Konrad, 1972-1983 (Box 30)
    - Kretzulesco, Emanuela, 1970-1977 (Box 30)
    - Krebs-Kruse (Box 30)
    - Kruckmann, Oluf, 1947-1982 (Box 31)
    - Kubow-Kyle (Box 31)
    - Kuttner, Stephen 1943-1994 (Box 31)
    - Kuntz, Marion and Paul 1969-1987, (5 Folders) (Box 31)
    - Kuntz, Marion and Paul 1988-1998 (Box 32)
    - Labalme, Patricia and George 1965-1988 (Box 32)
    - Labande-Ladwig (Box 32)
    - Lafferty-Lanza (Box 32)
    - Lapeyre-LaHanzi (Box 32)
    - Latz, Dorothy 1975-1994 (Box 32)
    - Lauder-Lazzarini (Box 32)
    - Leacock-LeFranc (Box 32)
    - Lehmann-LeMoine (Box 33)
    - Lemay, Helen 1974-1994 (Box 33)
    - Lemay, Richard 1953-1998 (Box 33)
    - Lencek-Lenzuni (Box 33)
    - Lenz, Fredrich 1934-1952 (Box 33)
    - Leppman, W.A. 1948-1993 (Box 33)
    - Leland-Letocha (Box 33)
    - Leuchtenburg-Levy (Box 33)
    - Lewent-Limentoni (Box 33)
    - Lind-Liu (Box 33)
    - Lloyd, Megan 1971-1993 (Box 33)
    - Lockwood, Dean 1939-1972 (Box 33)
    - Lock-Loewenick (Box 33)
    - Loewald, Hans 1925-1948 (Box 33)
    - Logan, George 1979-1983 (Box 34)
    - Logan, Marie Rose 1976-1988 (Box 34)
    - Logan-Lombardi (Box 34)
    - London-Loos (Box 34)
    - Lopez-Lovett (Box 34)
    - Lorch, Maristella 1951-1994 (Box 34)
    - Lowen-Lozzi (Box 34)
    - Lowe, E.A. 1939-1969 (Box 34)
    - Lowinsky, Edward 1942-1985 (Box 34)
    - Lublinsky-Lutzker (Box 34)
    - Ludwig, Walter 1968-1992 (Box 34)
    - Luzzati-Lyons (Box 34)
    - Lytle, Gary 1974-1983 (Box 34)
    - Macalaster-McClusky (Box 35)
    - MacClintock, Stuart 1950-1984 (Box 35)
    - McClure, George 1982-1988 (Box 35)
    - McConica-McCush (Box 35)
    - McCormick, Andrew 1979-1985 (Box 35)
    - McDaniel-McKinnon (Box 35)
    - McManamon, John 1975-1993 (Box 35)
    - McLaughlin-McSteen (Box 35)
    - Maaz-Mager (Box 35)
    - Maggi-Mallett (Box 35)
    - Mahoney, Edward 1962-1998 (Box 35)
    - Manasse, Ernst 1934-1989, (3 Folders) (Box 36)
    - Manasse, Mariane 1937-1970 (Box 36)
    - Mamelok-Manuel (Box 36)
    - Marachi-Mardi (Box 36)
    - Margolin, J.C. 1970-1994 (Box 36)
    - Margruder, Burnett and Judith 1956-1988 (Box 36)
    - Margulies-Markus (Box 36)
    - Mariano, N. 1938-1945 (Box 36)
    - Mark, Thomas 1972-1983 (Box 36)
    - Marks-Martelloti (Box 36)
    - Marti, Berthe 1954-1989 (Box 36)
    - Martin, C.1934-1984 (Box 36)
    - Martines, Lauro 1961-1985 (Box 36)
    - Martinhova, Dana 1961-1986 (Box 37)
    - Marti-Marzolo (Box 37)
    - Masai-Masotti (Box 37)
    - Massa, Eugenio 1958-1985 (Box 37)
    - Massey-Mastruzzi (Box 37)
    - Mates-Mattos (Box 37)
    - Matsen, Herbert 1954-1994, (3 Folders) (Box 37)
    - Maudlin-Mazzacane (Box 37)
    - Mazzarino-Mazzoni (Box 37)
    - MCI-Meisel (Box 37)
    - Meiss, Millard (Box 37)
    - Melczer-Melville (Box 37)
    - Memmo, Paul 1956-1976 (Box 37)
    - Menchi-Mentzer (Box 37)
    - Mercargolia- Merlo (Box 38)
    - Merlan, Phillip 1941-1970 (Box 38)
    - Merman-Messina (Box 38)
    - Methuen-Meyvaert (Box 38)
    - Meyer, Ann Marie 1966-1994 (Box 38)
    - Mian-Mikkleson (Box 38)
    - Milde, Wolfgang 1970-1995 (Box 38)
    - Milano-Milla (Box 38)
    - Miller, Clarence 1970-1983 (Box 38)
    - Miller-Milward (Box 38)
    - Miner-Mitterand (Box 38)
    - Model-Mommsen (Box 38)
    - Monfasi, John 1961-1993, (2 Folders) (Box 38)
    - Mondolfo-Mooney (Box 38)
    - Moody, Ernst 1942-1975 (Box 39)
    - Mooney, Michael 1974-1992 (Box 39)
    - More-Morewedge (Box 39)
    - Morey Family 1951-1993 (Box 39)
    - Morey-Mortiz (Box 39)
    - Moro-Mortz (Box 39)
    - Mosbacher-Moyihen (Box 39)
    - Motesiczy, Karl undated, 1927-1939, (3 Folders) (Box 39)
    - Motesiczy, Marie Louise (Box 39)
    - Mrockowski-Munzi (Box 39)
    - Mundy, John and Charlotte 1957-1998 (Box 39)
    - Muratori-Murphy (Box 39)
    - Murphy, James 1963-1993 (Box 40)
    - Murray-Myrno (Box 40)
    - Naber-Nahm (Box 40)
    - Naiden-Naylor (Box 40)
    - Nearing-Nelson (Box 40)
    - Nelson, Ben 1946-1975 (Box 40)
    - Nelson, John (Box 40)
    - Nenci, Giusseppe 1973-1986 (Box 40)
    - Nencioni, Giovanni 1976-1990 (Box 40)
    - Netreba-Negron (Box 40)
    - Newman, Eva and Randolph 1971-1976, (3 Folders) (Box 40)
    - Nibel, G. 1929 (Box 40)
    - Nicgorski-Nitscke (Box 40)
    - Noack-Norwood (Box 41)
    - Norton, David 1976-1983 (Box 41)
    - Nosal-Noyer (Box 41)
    - Nuccia-Nystedt (Box 41)
    - Oberman, Heiko 1962-1994 (Box 41)
    - Oakeshott- O'Connor (Box 41)
    - O'Connell-Oeyer (Box 41)
    - Oehler, K. 1962-1979 (Box 41)
    - Ogle-Olivieri (Box 41)
    - Olms, Georg 1963-1969 (Box 41)
    - Olson-Olton (Box 41)
    - Olschki, Aldo and Adele 1936-1963 (Box 41)
    - Olschki,Alessandro 1965-1989 (Box 41)
    - Olschki, Kate and Cesare 1961-1984 (Box 41)
    - Olschki,Leonardo 1934-1959 (Box 41)
    - Olschki, Leo S. 1936-1989 (Box 41)
    - O' Malley, John 1967-1993 (Box 41)
    - O'Malley, Onis (Box 41)
    - Ongano-Oppler (Box 42)
    - Oppenheimer, Ilse 1937-1958 (Box 42)
    - Oppenheimer, Klaus 1945-1976 (Box 42)
    - Ortali, Raymond 1980-1984 (Box 42)
    - Osborne-Ozmet (Box 42)
    - Paatz- Palumbo (Box 42)
    - Pampaloni-Papuli (Box 42)
    - Panofsky, E. 1938-1990 (Box 42)
    - Paradisi-Partee (Box 42)
    - Pascal- Payne (Box 42)
    - Pauck, Wilhelm and Marion 1968-1994 (Box 42)
    - Paz, Ramon 1953-1984 (Box 42)
    - Pedretti, Carl, 1967-1970 (Box 42)
    - Peale-Peiser (Box 43)
    - Peebles, Bernard 1956-1980 (Box 43)
    - Pelikan-Pepper (Box 43)
    - Penham, Daniel 1954-1993 (Box 43)
    - Percival, W.K. 1973-1984 (Box 43)
    - Percy-Perry (Box 43)
    - Perom, Paolo (Box 43)
    - Perosa, A. 1936-1995 (Box 43)
    - Perreiah, Alan 1979-1993 (Box 43)
    - Pescarolo-Pezzi (Box 43)
    - Pettee, C. 1967-1994 (Box 43)
    - Pgau-Photiades (Box 43)
    - Piaia-Pinegar (Box 43)
    - Piest-Pini (Box 43)
    - Pine, Martin 1958-1994 (Box 44)
    - Pnieder, G.B. 1952-1963 (Box 44)
    - Pinkus-Pizzaniglio (Box 44)
    - Piovani,Pietro 1977-1979 (Box 44)
    - Pipa. A. 1960-1968 (Box 44)
    - Pisa Books, 1984-1989 (Box 44)
    - Plante, Julian 1967-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 44)
    - Plachy-Pluta (Box 44)
    - Pocock-Pohlsander (Box 44)
    - Polak, Emil 1975-1994 (Box 44)